

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering
Manuel L. Quezon University,
Manila, Philippines, 1991

PROFESSIONElectrical Engineer

NATIONALITY Filipino

MEMBERSHIPS

ACPE - Electrical Engineer Registration No.ACPE-01434/PH Asean Chartered Professional Engineering Coordinating Committee Manila City, Philippines, Feb.2016

ASEAN Engineer Registration No.AE-6706 Asean Engineering Register (AER) Penana, Malaysia, Nov.2015

ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor Registration No. 120760 BSCIC / CQI-IRCA State of Qatar, Aug. 2018

Professional Electrical Engineer License: PEE 3580 Professional Regulation Commission Manila, Philippines, Sept.2013

Electrical Engineer Grade "A" Registration No. 3247 Ministry of Municipality and Environment, (MME-UPDA) State of Qatar, Nov.2011

Electrical Engineer Category "B" Registration No.EPP/FB/115/EL/02-B Committee for Organizing Engineering Professional Practice, (COEPP) Kingdom of Bahrain, Jan.2009

LANGUAGES English, Tagalog

Voltaire J. Cabreros, PEE, ACPE, AER

Engineering Manager
Professional Electrical Engineer- Reg.No.PEE-3580
ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor – Reg. No. 120760

Email: engr.vcabreros@gmail.com / Mobile: 0945-359-7789 / 0917-137-9770

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Mr. Cabreros, has over 24 yrs. combined experience in electrical design, construction & project management, QA/QC implementation, supply-chain management, facility management, building maintenance, project implementation, handing over/testing & commissioning of various electrical equipment (ex. switchgears, transformers, generators, motors & pumps) for high rise buildings, malls, hotels, residential, commercial projects, telecommunication facilities, light railway transit (LRT) projects, including pumping stations and data centers. Knowledgeable and experience in conducting QMS lead audit process and procedures. In relation, 18 yrs. of his experience was gained in working in the middle-east such as Saudi Arabia, Bahrain and Qatar. His professional experiences involve working in Engineering Consultancy firms like KEO & Syrconsult for the Qatar Petroleum District project & Bahrain ERA Tower project respectively, as a Consultant. He is a certified & licensed professional electrical engineer in the Philippines. He also passed his engineering committee accreditation in the Kingdom of Bahrain and is listed in the Ministry of Municipality and Urban Planning of Qatar as Grade "A" electrical engineer. Among other qualifications, he is also a registered ASEAN Engineer (AER), ASEAN Chartered Professional Engineer (ACPE) and a certified ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KINETIC Phils. Electrical Construction, Inc. Caloocan City, Philippines

Engineering Manager, July 2019 – Present

1) Confer with management, operations & engineering staff to discuss project specifications & procedures. 2) Coordinate & direct projects, making detailed plans to accomplish goals & directing the integration of technical activities. 3) Analyze technology, resource needs, market demand and assess the feasibility of projects. 4) Plan, direct, execute, control & monitoring of supply-chain management activities with the objective related to sustainability and risk management 5) Plan & direct the installation, testing, operation, maintenance & repair of facilities and equipment. 6) Direct, review & approve project designs and changes. 7) Recruit employees assign, direct & evaluate their work and oversee the development and performance of engineering staff competence. 8) Prepare budgets, bids & contracts and direct the negotiation of research tender project proposals. 9) Develop and implement policies, standards and procedures for the engineering and technical work performed in the department, service or project site. 10) Perform administrative functions such as reviewing and writing reports, approving expenditures of the department, enforcing rules, and making decisions about the purchase of materials or services. 11) Review and recommend or approve contracts and cost estimates. 12) Present and explain proposals, reports, and findings to management and clients. 13) Consult or negotiate with clients to prepare project specifications. 14) Set technical goals & timelines within broad outlines provided by top management. 15) Plan, direct, and coordinate assigned work & activities to engineering staff.

Engineering Manager

Professional Electrical Engineer- Reg.No.PEE-3580

ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor - Reg. No. 120760

Email: engr.vcabreros@gmail.com / Mobile: 0945-359-7789 / 0917-137-9770

REDCO INTERNATIONAL, Doha, Qatar

QA/QC Manager - MEP, Feb. 2018 – Mar. 2019

As QA/QC Manager he is responsible for ensuring that the quality management system (QMS) is fully implemented in an organized and efficient manner. He is responsible for delegating and assigning tasks to QA/QC Engineers / Inspectors and working closely with related to engineering, construction, design, material and fabrication. Manage and oversee project quality to ensure compliance to codes, standards, regulations, equipment specifications and QMS requirements. Advancing the quality achievement & performance improvement throughout the organization. Managing the development and implementation of the QMS for planning, fabrication, inspection, documentation, and operations activities. Define & planning the duties of QA/QC staff and related work schedules. Develop & establishing the service standards for end users. Identifying and developing QA/QC personnel certification requirements and continuing education/training needs. Provide leadership, mentorship, and direction of all QA/QC personnel. Responsible as the hold-point releases once all QMS functions have been completed. Oversee supervision of all visual inspections, including 3rd party subcontractors. Managing inspection and testing plans for new construction, repair work, and alterations. Identify and develop solutions to correct inspection functional deficiencies.

VOLTAS Limited, Doha, Qatar

Project Manager - Electrical, July 2016 - Feb 2018

His responsibilities are to plan and coordinate all aspects of the construction process related to design, construction management, electrical QA/QC works including commercial, hiring contractors, coordinating with other disciplines, trades and suppliers. Design preparation and review electrical schedule loads, single line diagrams and electrical designs & schematic for submission to suppliers for switchgears, MCC, MDB and DB fabrication. Design involves preparation & layout of lighting and power system. Manage and designate design tasks to a team of electrical engineers. Monitor design progress and final review of design drawings. Involve in the site management, coordination, Quality Assurance and Quality Control. Oversee the final surveillance inspection verified by QC inspectors. Coordinate with the Construction Manager on all quality issues at site. He also participates in the conceptual development of the project and oversees its organization, scheduling and implementation. He reports directly to the Project Director and updates him regarding the progress of the project.

KEO International Consultants, Doha, Qatar

Electrical Engineer / QAQC Engineer, May 2011 – June 2016

As Electrical Engineer of PM-CM Division, Mr. Cabreros is responsible for managing and Quality assurance of all electrical installations of the (QP) Qatar Petroleum District Project. In addition to interfacing with contractors, consultants, other trades and disciplines. Design review and approval, of electrical schedule loads, single line diagrams and electrical designs submitted by the main contractor. He also provides technical reviews of shop drawings, as-builts, RFI's, material submittals, method statements, electrical specifications, ensuring all regulations are followed as per KAHRAMAA and other engineering standards. He also monitors the daily and monthly electrical progress activity of the project, ensure minimal occurrence of site deficiencies.

Engineering Manager

Professional Electrical Engineer- Reg.No.PEE-3580

ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor - Reg. No. 120760

Email: engr.vcabreros@gmail.com / Mobile: 0945-359-7789 / 0917-137-9770

SYRCONSULT International, Manama, Bahrain

Sr. Electrical Engineer, May 2008 – May 2011

Acting head of Electrical Design team of the company. Prepare and design electrical schedule loads, single line diagrams, electrical drawings & schematics for tendering works as per client's requirements. Perform quality assurance and review of shop drawings related to power, lighting, ELV and Fire alarm systems. Act as supervision consultant at the site. Manage & supervise electrical installations, make sure that they are being followed as per project specifications. Approve & review contractors shop drawings, construction methods, RFI's & materials. Check & verify that all drawings are compliant with the local regulations, international codes & standards. Coordinate with other disciplines architectural, structural, ID, civil, & mechanical, in the design stages of the project. Witness the testing & commissioning of electrical equipments. Monitor progress of electrical works for compliance in accordance with the construction schedule. Provide technical information during project implementation & attend coordination meetings with clients & contractors.

JAL International, Dammam, Saudi Arabia

Electrical Design & Cost Engineer, February 2007 – March 2008

As Design & Cost Engineer of JAL International, an accredited manpower contractor for Saudi ARAMCO, part of his responsibilities was to prepare and design electrical schedule loads, single line diagrams, electrical shop drawings & schematics. Design includes the preparation of electrical load calculations, transformer sizing, cable sizing, circuit breaker sizing, panel board sizing, single line diagram, schematic diagram, BOQ including scope of works. Provide engineering technical assistance for Saudi Aramco, Technical Support Division. In addition he reviews and plan various maintenance job orders, evaluate materials and man hours to be utilize for the project and conduct site visits of the project area. Mr. Cabreros was also responsible for coordinating with proponents regarding actual job requirements of the project and reports directly to the MEP Superintendent regarding status of the projects.

Great Trade Construction Company, Pasay City, Philippines

Sr. Electrical Engineer, January 2005 – February 2007

As Senior Electrical Engineer his primary duties was to review and familiarize approved design drawings prior to construction and study material specifications as per scope of work, inspect and supervise electrical installations. Make sure that they are being followed as per approved design drawings and standards. Monitor all the electrical work progress within construction period and involve in the planning and budgeting exercises, pertaining to labor, materials and invoices as part of the operational expenditures of the Company. In addition he also provided technical information for project proposals and preparation of technical documents as required in private and government biddings. Involve in the hiring of new electrical engineers for ongoing projects of the company and liaise with different government agencies for electrical permits and other engineering submittals.

Engineering Manager

Professional Electrical Engineer- Reg.No.PEE-3580

ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor - Reg. No. 120760

Email: engr.vcabreros@gmail.com / Mobile: 0945-359-7789 / 0917-137-9770

Al-Hoty Establishment, Al-Khobar, Saudi Arabia

System Engineer - Electrical, August 2000 - December 2004

As Systems Engineer of Al-Hoty Establishment, an accredited manpower contractor of Saudi ARAMCO, he was involved in the preparation of electrical design of the office building for the SSD, Saudi ARAMCO. The design involves the layout of computer systems location plan, local area network cabling, power and lighting systems. He acted as coordinator regarding request for installation of new electrical equipments. Such as Un-Interrupted Power Supply, installation of additional power outlets, lighting, wiring and cabling works. Furthermore he also monitors the performance of facility equipment such as generators, transformers, UPS systems and scheduled the maintenance service of these systems.

5M Star Builders Inc., Valenzuela City, Philippines

Electrical Engineer, July 1994 – July 2000

As Electrical Engineer, his primary duty was to design lighting and power layout shop drawings. Prepare schedule of loads and bill of materials. Prepare single line diagrams. Design, edit and update electrical plans as per specification. Check and review electrical plans. Inspect and supervise electrical installations. Make sure that they are being followed as per standard. In addition Mr. Cabreros was also involved in the preventive maintenance planning and schedule of electrical equipment's that were used for construction. He also initiated and supervised the trouble-shooting of electrical equipment.

PERSONAL DATA

Birthdate : February 8, 1970

Birthplace : Manila City, Philippines

Age : 50

Civil Status : Married (with 3 children)
Spouse : Aguida V. Cabreros, DBA
Occupation : College/University Professor

Father : Gerardo T. Cabreros, PME, DBA, DPA, PhD.

Occupation : PRC Board Examiner
Mother : Marietta J. Cabreros

Occupation : Housewife

No. of Siblings : 2 - (1 brother & 1 sister)

RELEVANT PROJECT EXPERIENCE

KINETIC Phils. Electrical Construction Projects: (Construction Management)

- Google Cebu Ebloc 5 Project Cebu I.T. Park, Lahug, Cebu City
- MRT-3 Electrical Power Maintenance Depot Area Trinoma, Quezon City
- LRT-2 Cable Installation and Rehabilitation Project Depot Area, Pasig City
- Emerald Hotel Resort & Casino Project Cebu City
- S&R C5 & New Manila Project

Engineering Manager

Professional Electrical Engineer- Reg.No.PEE-3580

ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor - Reg. No. 120760

Email: engr.vcabreros@gmail.com / Mobile: 0945-359-7789 / 0917-137-9770

REDCO Project: (Project & Construction Management)

- Qatar Rail Green Line Project Underground Tunnel Doha, Qatar
- Qatar Rail Hamad International Airport Station Doha, Qatar
- Qatar Rail Qatar University Station Doha, Qatar
- Qatar Rail Mall of Qatar Station Doha, Qatar

VOLTAS Project: (Design, Build & Construction Management)

Vendome Mall - Lusail City, State of Qatar

KEO Projects: (Design Review & Construction Management)

- Qatar Petroleum District Project (9 office towers & 1 hotel) Doha, Qatar
- The Pearl Project: "Porto Arabia A & B" (highrise residential tower) Doha, Qatar
- Regent Hotel Project Doha, Qatar

Syrconsult Projects: (Design & Construction Management)

- ERA Tower (50 storey high rise residential) Seef Area, Bahrain
- SUKOON Tower (46 storey high rise hotel & residential) Juffair Area, Bahrain
- LARI Tower (20 storey high rise residential) Juffair Area, Bahrain
- DATA CENTER Ministry of Education (4 storey government building) Bahrain
- EDAMAH Twin Tower (36 storey government building) Bahrain
- Times Square Tower (25 storey building) Bahrain
- Gulf Investment Tower (33 storey building) Bahrain

Saudi ARAMCO Projects: (Design & Construction Supervision)

- Lighting Upgrade Project in CORE Area Buildings (ENG'G, EXPEC, ADMIN) Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
- Electrical Rehabilitation Project of Warehouse Building at L.I.P. Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
- Emergency Lights Upgrade Project at ENG'G and EXPEC building Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
- Installation of New Power Panel Boards Project at Tower building Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
- Cooling Tower Photocell Lighting Upgrade Project at EXPEC building Dhahran, Saudi Arabia
- Annual Power Shutdown for EXPEC and ENG'G Bldg. (Planning Coordinator) Dhahran, Saudi Arabia

Engineering Manager

Professional Electrical Engineer- Reg.No.PEE-3580

ISO 9001:2015 Lead Auditor - Reg. No. 120760

Email: engr.vcabreros@gmail.com / Mobile: 0945-359-7789 / 0917-137-9770

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

- Awarded Most Outstanding Chapter Member Institute of Integrated Electrical Engineers of the Philippines, Eastern Region Chapter Saudi Arabia, Dec. 2007
- Awarded Senior Member Status Institute of Integrated Electrical Engineers of the Philippines National Chapter – Quezon City, Philippines, Nov. 2014
- Awarded Most Outstanding Alumni Manuel L. Quezon University Engineering Alumni & Faculty Association Inc. Quezon City, Philippines, Nov. 11, 2017

(References & Supporting Documents will be provided upon request)